Inventory of the Richard De Rochemont papers, 1900-1997
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
- Series III. Personal and professional files, 1916-1982
  - Personal - certificates, 1947, undated (Box 177)
  - Personal - certificates, 1960-1980 (Box 199)
  - Personal - certificates, 1947, 1976 (Box 205)
  - Personal - engagement calendars and diaries, 1934-1982 (Box 176)
  - Personal - farm matters, 1942-1950 (Box 180)
  - Personal - financial records, 1959, 1968-1974, 1982 (Box 187)
  - Personal - Flemington - new house, 1962-1964 (Box 180)
  - Personal - garden, 1982 (Box 177)
  - Personal - horoscope, 1953, 1967 (Box 178)
  - Personal - Inventory, 1972 (Box 178)
  - Personal - Landsdowne House, undated (Box 178)
  - Personal - letters of introduction, 1941-1949 (Box 177)
  - Personal - Louis De Rochemont - death, 1979 (Box 177)
  - Personal - medical files, 1979-1981 (Box 177)
  - Personal - membership cards, undated (Box 176)
  - Personal - memberships, 1946-1977 (Box 177)
  - Personal - Michigan State plate, 1964 (Box 205)
  - Personal - Michigan State Sigma Pi Eta paddle, 1964 (Box 205)
  - Personal - miscellaneous correspondence and papers, circa 1916-1970 (Box 206)
  - Personal - name button, undated (Box 205)
  - Personal - passports, undated (Box 176)
  - Personal - Richard De Rochemont obituaries, 1982 (Box 206)
  - Personal - School notebook, 1927 (Box 177)
  - Polymetrics International, 1971 (Box 179)
  - Pontlevoy, 1944-1973 (Box 180)
  - Psychiatry periodical, 1968 (Box 178)
  - Publicity, 1943-1952 (Box 181)
  - Refugees, 1941 (Box 179)
  - Research file - France, 1940 (Box 178)
  - Research file - Free French, 1981 (Box 178)
  - Research file - North Africa, Portugal, Spain, 1941-1943 (Box 179)
  - Resume - Jean A. Cherasse, undated (Box 179)
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 177)
  - Signed print of J. Edgar Hoover (copy), 1941 (Box 181)
  - Signed print of J. Edgar Hoover (original), 1941 (Box 215)
  - Speeches, 1940-1955 (Box 181)
  - Stationery and envelopes, undated (Box 179)
  - Testimonials and souvenirs, 1943-1948 (Box 177)
  - Trips - Algiers, Rome, 1944 (Box 182)
  - Trips - Canada, 1940 (Box 182)
  - Trips - Europe, 1941-1950, 1972 (Box 182)
  - Trips - Europe (Great Britain, France, Germany) - War Department Newsreel Group, 1945 (Box 182)
  - Trips - Europe (Vichy France, Portugal, Spain), 1941 (Box 182)
  - Trips - European correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box 182)
  - Trips - London, 1940-1941 (Box 182)
  - Trips - London - March of Time (MOT), 1937-1940 (Box 182)
  - Trips - Paris correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 182)
  - United States Government Coordinator of Information (C.O.I.), 1942 (Box 179)
  - Vavin, 1972 (Box 179)
  - Vavin - administrative and legal, 1951-1964 (Box 179)
  - Vavin - camera equipment insurance, 1974-1976 (Box 179)
  - Vavin - dope sheets, 1957 (Box 187)
  - Vavin - financial records, 1963-1971 (Box 178)
  - Vavin - financial records, 1967-1974 (Box 186-187)
  - Vavin - financial records, 1968-1974 (Box 184)
  - Vavin - financial records - accountant's reports, 1950-1975 (Box 187)
  - Vavin - financial records - stock certificates and ledger, undated (Box 184)
  - Vavin - Ford contract - Lincoln series, 1952-1955 (Box 179)
  - Vavin - Gerald E. Weiler vs. Vavin, Inc., 1958-1974 (Box 188)
  - Vavin - legal and contractual correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 179)
  - Vavin - minutes and by-laws, 1948-1971 (Box 184)
  - Vavin - miscellaneous, undated (Box 179)
  - Vavin - stationery and envelopes, undated (Box 179)
  - Vavin - wine scene clips and notes, undated (Box 179)
  - War correspondent documents, circa 1944-1946 (Box 176)
  - World War II in France and French resistance scrapbooks (disassembled - newspaper and magazine clippings), 1940-1944 (Box 195-198)
  - WWII propaganda poster (Africa), undated (Box 205)
- Series IV. Films, 1936-1972
  Includes films produced, written, or directed by De Rochemont. Contains 4 sub-series: Reader’s Digest, March of Time, French Government Tourist Office, and Informational and other. Many of the films include the final print, originals and clips, and inter-negatives.
  - Sub-series 1. Reader's Digest Association, 1949-1971
    Arranged alphabetically by title. Contains films produced by De Rochemont and his production company, Vavin, Inc., for Reader’s Digest Association.
    - "10 Ways to Cut Your Medical Bills" (color), 1966 October (Box 21)
    - "400,000 Boys Are Members of the Club" (b&w), 1956 February (Box 1)
    - "Agriculture's Fantastic New Machines" (color), 1965 February (Box 20)
    - "Air Traffic Controller" (b&w), 1961 September (Box 1)
    - "Air View of Southern Change" (b&w), 1955 October (Box 1)
    - "America's Amazing Women" (b&w), 1955 July (Box 1)
    - "America's House of Braille and Talking Books" (b&w), 1958 October (Box 1)
    - "An Answer at Last to Collisions in the Sky?" (color), 1969 July (Box 20)
    - "Antwerp's Glitter Street - World Diamond Center" (b&w), 1959 June (Box 1)
    - "Are You Disturbed By the New Religion?" (color), 1968 February (Box 20)
    - "At Large and 'Most Wanted' Ten Dangerous Men" (b&w), 1964 March (Box 1)
    - "Atomic Power Comes to Age" (color), 1965 December (Box 20)
    - "Awful Truth About the U.S. Post Office" (color), 1968 November (Box 20)
    - "Battle Against Mail Order Pornography" (b&w), 1964 February (Box 4)
    - "Battle of San Francisco Bay" (color), 1969 March (Box 20)
    - "Big 'Ifs' Ahead for Atom Power" (b&w), 1958 August (Box 2)
    - "Big Traffic Jam In the Sky" (b&w), 1956 July (Box 1)
    - "Biggest Fourth of July Salute" (b&w), 1964 July (Box 1)
    - "Black Power of Whitney Young" (color), 1969 January (Box 20)
    - "Boeing 747: The About-To-Be Behemoth" (b&w), 1968 May (Box 4)
    - "Boom That Follows the Highways" (b&w), 1959 December (Box 1)
    - "Box That Catches Criminals" (b&w), 1964 April (Box 1)
    - "Boys on the Cliff" (b&w), 1961 August (Box 1)
    - "Campus Crisis" (color), undated (Box 70)
    - "Can We Stand Strikes By Teachers, Police, Garbage Men, Etc.?" (color), 1969 August (Box 21)
    - "Case for Year-Round Schools" (color), 1966 December (Box 20)
    - "City That Pulled Itself Together" (color), 1967 July (Box 20)
    - "Civic Beauty Is Good Business" (b&w), 1962 March (Box 1)
    - "Civic Watchdogs in High Heels" (b&w), 1957 June (Box 1)
    - "Clearing House for College Hopefuls" (b&w), 1962 April (Box 1)
    - "Columbia: Mightiest Power Builder on Earth" (b&w), 1958 May (Box 1)
    - "Conversation with Vice President Agnew" (color), undated (Box 132-138)
    - "Conversation with Vice President Agnew" (color), undated (Box 140)
    - "Crisis In the Post Office" (color), 1966 March (Box 20)
    - "Crisis In U.S. Transportation" (b&w), 1963 January (Box 4)
    - "Crisis on Campus" (color), 1969 June (Box 21)
    - "Danger Rides In Small Boats" (b&w), 1963 August (Box 1)
    - "Day In the Life of an Airport" (color), 1949 February (Box 20)
    - "Detectives In Smocks" (color), 1970 January (Box 20)
    - "'Doc' Draper's Wonderful Tops" (b&w), 1957 September (Box 2)
    - "Drama Behind the Crop Forecasting" (b&w), 1955 August (Box 1)
    - "Drama of Offshore Oil" (b&w), 1957 July (Box 1)
    - "Eight Women" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 15)
    - "Electoral College" (color), undated (Box 25)
    - "Empty Seats In the Cockpit" (color), 1967 June (Box 20)
    - "Expo '67: Canada's Billion Dollar Birthday Party" (color), 1967 April (Box 20)
    - "Fantastic Hazards of Landing on the Moon" (b&w), 1963 September (Box 3)
    - "FBI Wants This Man" (b&w), 1961 March (Box 1)
    - "Fight for America's Alps" (color), 1967 May (Box 21)
    - "Five Faces of Alaska" (color), 1965 September (Box 20)
    - "Five Wonders of the Wilderness" (b&w), 1962 May (Box 3)
    - "Flood Prevention That Works" (b&w), 1956 June (Box 1)
    - "Florida: Sunshine, Sea and Social-Security" (b&w), 1959 July (Box 1)
    - "Fly Far Away With Your Family" (color), 1971 April (Box 20)
    - "Flying - Questions" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 66)
    - "Flying Family," (color), undated (Box 141)
    - "For Auto Accident Victims -- A New Kind of Insurance" (b&w), 1961 May (Box 1)
    - "Four Miracles - And a Masterpiece" (color), 1966 November (Box 20)
    - "Four Professors and the Welfare Revolution" (color), 1970 January (Box 20)
    - "From the Brink of Extinction" (color), 1969 April (Box 20)
    - "Give Us the Tools" (b&w), 1959 November (Box 1)
    - "Glamour of the Everglades" (b&w), 1956 January (Box 1)
    - "Gordie Howe: Hockey's Marvelous Methuselah" (color), 1969 November (Box 20)
    - "Gordie Howe: Hockey's Marvelous Methuselah" (color), undated (Box 57)
    - "Grand Hotel at 30 Knots", undated (Box 210)
    - "Greatest Bible of the All" (b&w), 1956 January (Box 1)
    - "Handbook of First Aid" (b&w), 1960 September (Box 1)
    - "Have You Checked Your Tires Lately?" (color), 1965 July (Box 20)
    - "Headquarters for Precision" (b&w), 1958 November (Box 1)
    - "Health Careers Unlimited" (color), 1965 August (Box 20)
    - "Help Wanted: Engineers and Scientists" (color), 1967 February (Box 20)
    - "Here's How Inflation Has Victimized You and the Worst Is Yet to Come" (b&w), 1959 March (Box 1)
    - "How Baltimore Fends Off Riots" (color), 1968 March (Box 20)
    - "How Our Troops Are Trained for Combat" (b&w), 1961 October (Box 1)
    - "How the Doctor Examines Your Eyes" (b&w), 1960 October (Box 1)
    - "How to Double Your Learning Power" (color), 1967 April (Box 20)
    - "How to End Our Post Office Mess - Permanently" (b&w), 1958 February (Box 4)
    - "How to Feel Fit at Any Age" (color), 1968 March (Box 20)
    - "How to Get the Most Out of the N.Y. World's Fair" (color), 1965 May (Box 20)
    - "How to Have More School for Less Money" (b&w), 1959 February (Box 1)
    - "How We Help the Communists Win the Propaganda War" (color), 1966 November (Box 22)
    - "Hurricane Warning" (color), 1969 September (Box 20)
    - "Hurricane Warning" (color unfinished cuts), undated (Box 40)
    - "Hurricane Warning" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 142)
    - "I Hit and Ran" (b&w), 1961 February (Box 1)
    - "ICU - Newest Thing in Nursing" (b&w), 1964 November (Box 1)
    - "If You Have an Accident" (b&w), 1965 January (Box 1)
    - "Interview With Vice-President Agnew" (color), 1970 February (Box 23)
    - "Introduction to Outer Space" (b&w), 1958 June (Box 1)
    - "Is Congress Destroying Itself?" (color), 1969 April (Box 20)
    - "Is Your Child's School Safe From Fire?" (b&w), 1959 October (Box 1)
    - "Is Your Family Safe From Death By Fire?" (b&w), 1960 May (Box 1)
    - "Jacksonville's Jury of Juvenile Peers" (b&w), 1958 June (Box 1)
    - "Jamboree '67", 1967 (Box 210)
    - "Japan's Two-Mile-A-Minute Train" (color), 1965 April (Box 21)
    - "John F. Kennedy School No. 1" (color), 1965 March (Box 21)
    - "Judo - Mayhem With a Gentle Tough" (color), 1965 September (Box 21)
    - "Jumping Angels of the USAF" (b&w), 1962 November (Box 3)
    - "Landing Lights" (b&w), 1959 April (Box 3)
    - "Legacy of Thomas Jefferson" (b&w), 1963 March (Box 1)
    - "Lessons of History" (color), 1968 December (Box 20)
    - "Let’s Close Ranks on the Homefront" (color), 1968 April (Box 20)
    - "Let's Close the Muscle Gap" (b&w), 1961 November (Box 3)
    - "Let's Take Our Ships Out of the Bottle" (color), 1967 February (Box 21)
    - "Library for All the Nation" (color), 1967 December (Box 21)
    - "Lilliputian World of the Bonsai" (color), 1967 September (Box 20)
    - "Little Red Schoolhouse Goes Modern" (color), 1966 October (Box 21)
    - "Living Legacy of Walt Disney" (color), 1967 June (Box 21)
    - "Look at America's New Towns" (color), 1967 March (Box 20)
    - "Look What’s Happening to Glass!" (color), 1967 December (Box 21)
    - "Look What's Happened to Houseboats" (color), 1967 July (Box 21)
    - "Low Budget Miracle In Foreign Aid" (b&w), 1960 January (Box 2)
    - "Madame Tussaud Waxes Modern" (color), 1968 October (Box 23)
    - "Magic World of Dolls" (b&w), 1964 December (Box 1)
    - "Make Our Neighborhood Roads Safer Now" (color), 1966 September (Box 20)
    - "Man's Most Playful Friend: The Land Otter" (b&w), 1956 October (Box 4)
    - "Maxim's Famous Meals Take to the Air" (b&w), 1958 December (Box 3)
    - "Mayhem on Ice" (color), 1966 March (Box 21)
    - "Mayor With the Perfect Jail Record" (b&w), 1958 January (Box 1)
    - "Medicine's F.B.I." (b&w), 1959 May (Box 3)
    - "Medico" (b&w), 1962 January (Box 3)
    - "Meet the 'Monster' That Checks Your Taxes" (color), 1967 January (Box 21)
    - "Money Does Grow on Trees" (b&w), 1961 January (Box 3)
    - "Most Phenomenal Athletes In History" (b&w), 1964 October (Box 3)
    - "My Eight Beautiful Mistresses" (color), 1969 January (Box 20)
    - "Needed: A National Presidential Primary" (color), 1968 July (Box 21)
    - "Needed: A Realistic East-West Trade Policy" (color), 1969 June (Box 22)
    - "Needed: New Directions For Rural America" (color), 1968 September (Box 22)
    - "New Age of Railroads" (b&w), 1957 May (Box 1)
    - "New Cure for Boredom In the Classroom" (color), 1966 May (Box 20)
    - "New Look at Niagara Falls" (b&w), 1957 August (Box 1)
    - "New York's Multi-Million Dollar 'Village Green'" (color), 1967 October (Box 21)
    - "No More Overhead Wires!" (color), 1967 November (Box 22)
    - "Nobody Needs to Drown" (b&w), 1960 July (Box 3)
    - "Odd Little Isle of Aruba" (b&w), 1957 January (Box 2)
    - "One Man's Crusade for Everybody's Freedom" (b&w), 1964 June (Box 3)
    - "Our Reckless Presidential Lottery" (color), 1969 May (Box 21)
    - "Parents Across the Sea" (b&w), 1963 February (Box 3)
    - "Parks That Pay for Themselves" (b&w), 1963 November (Box 1)
    - "Pastor of Peachtree Street" (b&w), 1961 June (Box 2)
    - "Patio Party…The Breakfast Shopper" (color), undated (Box 23)
    - "Pied Piper From Peoria" (color), 1968 April (Box 20)
    - "Pipelines Are Booming" (b&w), 1957 March (Box 1)
    - "Plain Talk About Hatred and Violence" (color), 1968 June (Box 20)
    - "Population Explosion" (b&w), 1962 February (Box 3)
    - "Profiteers Are Wrecking Medicaid" (color), 1969 October (Box 21)
    - "Promise of Classroom Television" (b&w), 1960 November (Box 2)
    - "Queen of the Adriatic Needs Our Help" (color), 1966 February (Box 21)
    - "Questions People Ask About Flying" (color), 1970 August (Box 21)
    - "Race to Save Abu Simbel" (color), 1966 January (Box 23)
    - "Radial-Plies: A Dramatic Advance In Tires" (color), 1967 March (Box 21)
    - "Railroads Are Fighting Back" (color), 1965 October (Box 22)
    - "REA: A Case Study of Bureaucracy Run Wild" (b&w), 1963 December (Box 3)
    - "Rescue Breathing" (b&w), 1959 August (Box 3)
    - "Rescue Squad Rolls On" (b&w), 1956 April (Box 3)
    - "Roy Williams: Mr. Civil Rights" (color), 1968 January (Box 21)
    - "Ruin for the Grand Canyon" (color), 1966 April (Box 21)
    - "Save the Everglades" (color), 1965 November (Box 20)
    - "School Where Fitness Counts" (b&w), 1964 September (Box 3)
    - "Screen Test For Tomorrow's Schools" (b&w), 1957 November (Box 3)
    - "Secret Service" (b&w), 1956 August (Box 4)
    - "Seven Wonders of American Engineering" (b&w), 1955 November (Box 3)
    - "Shot While Hunting" (b&w), 1962 October (Box 3)
    - "Should You Travel More?" (color), 1970 April (Box 20)
    - "Sing Out, America" (color), 1967 May (Box 22)
    - "Skiing's Good Samaritans" (color), 1965 September (Box 20)
    - "Skin Diving: One Part Fun, One Part Danger" (b&w), 1964 August (Box 2)
    - "Snowmobiles: The Cats That Conquered Winter" (b&w), 1968 December (Box 3)
    - "So You Don't Use Seat Belts" (b&w), 1963 July (Box 3)
    - "Soon You'll Be Flying the Polar Path" (b&w), 1956 December (Box 1)
    - "Standing Room Only on Spaceship Earth" (color), 1969 December (Box 21)
    - "Strange Case of the Country Slickers v. the City Rubes" (not released), 1960 (Box 210)
    - "Super Farmer Attacks Global Poverty" (color), 1968 January (Box 20)
    - "Tag That Can Save Your Life" (b&w), 1963 October (Box 3)
    - "Tailgating - Invitation to Tragedy" (color), 1965 October (Box 20)
    - "Team Teaching: How Good Is It?" (b&w), 1964 May (Box 3)
    - "Ted Williams: A Legend Returns To Baseball" (color), undated (Box 25)
    - "Ted Williams: A Legend Returns To Baseball" (color), 1969 July (Box 21)
    - "There's a Treasure In Toys" (b&w), 1957 December (Box 3)
    - "These Fighters Against Youth Crime Need Your Help" (b&w), 1961 April (Box 3)
    - "These Youngsters Are In Business" (b&w), 1955 September (Box 1)
    - "They 'Discover' America" (b&w), 1963 June (Box 3)
    - "They Grow Money on Trees" (color), 1968 November (Box 21)
    - "They Help Boys Want to Be Educated" (b&w), 1963 December (Box 1)
    - "They Listen to the Language of the Universe" (color), 1969 February (Box 21)
    - "They Ride on Cushions of Air" (b&w), 1960 February (Box 3)
    - "They Saved the Big Sur" (color), 1967 November (Box 20)
    - "They Turn Welfare Recipients Into Taxpayers" (color), 1968 September (Box 21)
    - "They Volunteered for Cancer" (b&w), 1958 April (Box 3)
    - "They're Doing Wonders With Aluminum" (2 copies), 1960 March (Box 3)
    - "Things You Learn at the Grand Canyon" (b&w), 1957 February (Box 3)
    - "Think Before You Drown!" (b&w), 1962 July (Box 3)
    - "This Country Needs Universal Military Training" (color), 1966 September (Box 21)
    - "This Is Our House, Y'See" (color), 1969 December (Box 21)
    - "This State Gets Tough With Speeders - And Saves Lives" (b&w), 1958 September (Box 3)
    - "Three Cheers For George Washington High" (b&w), 1958 March (Box 2)
    - "Tips to Mothers Who Drive" (color), 1968 April (Box 20)
    - "To Insure Domestic Tranquility" (color), 1968 March (Box 21)
    - "To Make Streets Safe After Dark" (b&w), 1960 June (Box 3)
    - "Tomorrow's Airports vs. the Ground Barrier" (color), 1967 September (Box 21)
    - "Tough Fruitful Life of the G.I. Guinea Pigs" (b&w), 1956 November (Box 3)
    - "Tragic Shortage of Transplant Hearts" (color), 1969 August (Box 21)
    - Transportation stock shots, undated (Box 6)
    - "U.S.A. Goes to the Fair" (b&w), 1955 December (Box 3)
    - "Unfolding Miracle of X-Rays" (color), 1967 January (Box 21)
    - "Utah - Unique Fantasy In Sand and Stone" (color), 1969 November (Box 21)
    - "VIP", 1971 (Box 143)
    - "V.I.P." (color), undated (Box 72)
    - "Wally Hickel - Activist From Anchorage" (color), 1970 February (Box 21)
    - "Wanted: Police Weapons That Do Not Kill" (color), 1968 February (Box 22)
    - "Washington National Cathedral: Our Nation's Spiritual Landmark" (color), 1966 February (Box 21)
    - "Watch the Whirlybird at Work" (color), 1965 November (Box 22)
    - "We Could Have Won In Vietnam Long Ago" (color), 1969 May (Box 21-22)
    - "We Must Put the Brakes On Federal Spending" (color), 1968 July (Box 21)
    - "We Must Stop Choking Our Cities" (color), 1966 August (Box 22)
    - "We Should Be Ashamed!" (color), 1967 August (Box 22)
    - "We Stand on Common Ground" (color), 1970 March (Box 21)
    - "Welcome Aboard the Awesome Big E" (b&w), 1962 December (Box 3)
    - "What Combat Does to Our Men" (color), 1968 June (Box 21)
    - "What Happens When You Drink" (b&w), 1957 April (Box 3)
    - "What Has Happened to America?" (color), 1967 October (Box 22)
    - "What Is Leadership?" (color), 1965 June (Box 21)
    - "What the Newest of the Plastics Can Do for Us" (b&w), 1959 January (Box 3)
    - "What Will Your Teenager Do This Summer?" (b&w), 1963 May (Box 3)
    - "What Would You Do In These Driving Emergencies?" (b&w), 1962 September (Box 3)
    - "What's New In the Woods?" (b&w), 1956 May (Box 3)
    - "When the Earthquakes Struck Chile" (b&w), 1960 December (Box 3)
    - "While Others Sleep" (b&w), 1957 October (Box 3)
    - "Who's Afraid of Automation?" (color), 1966 April (Box 22)
    - "Wonderful White Stallions of Vienna" (b&w), 1963 April (Box 3)
    - "Wonders of Direct Distance Dialing" (b&w), 1955 October (Box 3)
    - "Yosemite - Jewel of the Sierra" (b&w), 1961 July (Box 3)
    - "You Are a VIP When You Travel By Air" (color), 1972 January (Box 21)
    - "You Can Have Decent Traffic Courts" (b&w), 1964 January (Box 3)
    - "You'll Never Be Afraid to Try" (color), 1969 March (Box 21)
  - Sub-series 2. March of Time, 1936-1953
    Arranged alphabetically by title. Contains March of Time newsreel films.
    - "American Beauty" (volume 12, episode 2), 1945 October 5 (Box 19)
    - "America's New Air Power" (volume 14, episode 16), 1948 October 29 (Box 18)
    - "Asia's New Voice (India)" (volume 15, episode 2), 1949 February 18 (Box 17)
    - "Atomic Power" (volume 12, episode 13), 1946 August 9 (Box 19)
    - "Battle for Bread", circa 1950 (Box 18)
    - "Beauty at Work" (volume 16, episode 4), 1950 June 9 (Box 18)
    - "China", undated (Box 17)
    - "Cold War: Act 1 - France" (volume 14, episode 6), 1948 January 23 (Box 17)
    - "Cold War: Act II - Crisis In Italy" (volume 14, episode 8), 1948 March 19 (Box 17)
    - "Congress", undated (Box 19)
    - "Family - An Approach to Peace", circa 1949 (Box 18)
    - "Fight Game" (volume 14, episode 11), 1948 June 11 (Box 19)
    - "Germany - Handle With Care!" (volume 13, episode 6), 1947 January 24 (Box 17)
    - "Golden Twenties (aka A Chronicle of America's Jazz Age)", 1949 (Box 110-111)
    - "Is Everybody Happy?"/"Search For Happiness" (volume 13, episode 1), 1946 September 27 (Box 17)
    - "Life With Grandpa" (volume 14, episode 14), 1948 September 3 (Box 18)
    - "Life With Junior" (volume 14, episode 9), 1948 April 16 (Box 18)
    - "Mid-Century Half Way to Where?" (volume 16, episode 1), 1950 February 3 (Box 2)
    - "Modern Surgery", circa 1949 (Box 18)
    - "New France" (volume 12, episode 12), 1946 July 12 (Box 17)
    - "On Stage" (volume 15, episode 1), 1949 January 21 (Box 19)
    - "One Day of War - Russia 1943"/"Russia at War" (volume 9, episode 6), 1943 January (Box 17)
    - "Opportunity - Story of the Best Location in the Nation", undated (Box 2)
    - "Pacific Coast", undated (Box 18)
    - "Presidency" (volume 3, episode 3), 1936 November 6 (Box 19)
    - "Report on the Atom" (volume 15, episode 4), 1949 April 15 (Box 19)
    - "Rise and Fall of Nazi Germany: What To Do With Germany" (volume 11, episode 2), 1944 October (Box 17)
    - "Sport Car for the American Road", undated (Box 19)
    - "Supreme Court" (volume 3, episode 9), 1937 April 16 (Box 19)
    - "Sweden Looks Ahead" (volume 15, episode 5), 1949 May 13 (Box 17)
    - "Teachers' Crisis" (volume 13, episode 8), 1947 March 21 (Box 18)
    - "Travel: The Tourists' Europe", 1953 (Box 19)
    - "Two Worlds of France: Paris and the France Beyond", 1953 (Box 19)
  - Sub-series 3. French Government Tourist Office, 1955-1964
    Arranged alphabetically by title and subject. Contains informational films produced for the French Government Tourist Office (FGTO).
    - Alsace, Corsica, Paris (color), 1959 (Box 95)
    - Alsace, Corsica, Paris (color original rolls), undated (Box 96)
    - Alsace, Corsica, Paris - outtakes and originals (color), 1959 (Box 97)
    - "Artists of Provence" (b&w), 1955 (Box 5)
    - "Artists of Provence" (color), 1955 (Box 25)
    - "Bastille" (b&w), undated (Box 4)
    - "Bright New Face of Paris" (color), 1964 (Box 30)
    - "Bright New Face of Paris" (color), undated (Box 32)
    - "Bright New Face of Paris" (color original), undated (Box 53)
    - "Bright New Face of Paris" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 63)
    - Carcassonne, Roussillon (color original rolls), undated (Box 98)
    - "Carnaval de Nice" (sound), undated (Box 76)
    - "Carnival on the French Riviera" (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - "Carnival on the French Riviera" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 11)
    - "Chateau Country" (color), undated (Box 24)